Marshall Thompson Front-End Engineer

CALL ME 706.421.2816

WEB https://marshall.codes

EMAIL ME marshallthomp@gmail.com

GITHUB github.com/imarrsh

Hard-working, newly-minted Front-End Engineer passionate about shaping the future of the web. Experienced in CRUD development with a focus on front-end applications that utilize RESTful APIs to deliver data to an end user. Organized and methodical. Motivated to learn and expand on my craft.

EXPERIENCE

The Iron Yard

Greenville, SC

12-week immersive code school

STUDENT, FRONT-END ENGINEERING: SEPT. 2016–DEC. 2016

Applied concepts from lecture to assignments and met requirements of pushing code daily to a live production server. Gained intensive hands-on experience crafting projects that utilize current front-end technologies along with cutting edge frameworks, MVC architecture, unit testing, scaffolding tools, version control and more. Prior experience enabled helping fellow students on subject matter.

Ocozzio, Inc.

Augusta, GA

Marketing firm with national clients primarily in the healthcare payer space.

IT DIRECTOR: APR. 2014-AUG. 2016

Leadership role representing the tech department in weekly meetings. Reported to executive team on the status of various projects and initiatives, responsible for managing and working in a small development team and involved in decisions related to the technology stack, software and 3rd party services used to increase the marketing capability of clients. Led team in best practices and provided feedback on performance and expectations.

DEVELOPER/DESIGNER/PRINT TECH: NOV. 2010-AUG. 2016

Programmed highly customizable, branded materials for clients to serve their marketing needs through a VDP web-to-print software suite. Improvised on designs when needed due to the variable nature of documents. Ran the small, in-house digital printer for various small runs and rush jobs.

Cracker Barrel Old Country Store

Augusta, GA

GRILL COOK: JAN. 2006–JAN. 2011

Tasked with ensuring food was prepared correctly and in a timely manner within the quidelines of food safety regulations. Closed regularly and took pride in cleanup and restocking so that the next shift was ready to roll.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript: ES5/6, Front-End MVC Frameworks like React and Backbone, JSX, Handlebars, ¡Query, Underscore, Mocha & Chai, Testem

HTML/CSS: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap w/ Sass, RWD

Other handy skills: RESTful API's, Parse Server, Adobe InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, MS Office, PageFlex Studio/Storefront

EDUCATION

THE IRON YARD

Sept. 2016 - Dec. 2016 Front End Engineering

AUGUSTA TECHNICAL COLLEGE

Oct. 2007 - May 2010

Associates Degree: Media Communications

TOOLS:

Command Line, Git, GitHub, npm, Yeoman, Bower, HomeBrew, Browserify, Sass, ESLint, Sublime, Atom, VS Code